## ADITYA MAYANK SHANKAR

1102 Courtney Road Baltimore, MD21227 4439720857 imashankarr@qmail.com linkedin.com/in/adityashankarr/

#### **CAREER PROFILE**

A data-driven experienced professional and a graduate student with 4 years IT and research experience in data analytics, database design, and data visualization for large-scale complex data sets. Proven competence in improving efficiency and decreasing run times in multiple projects, for solving real world problems in fast paced teams.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Maryland Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD
 Graduation Date - May 2018

Master of Science in Information Sciences, CGPA: 3.6

• G.H Raisoni College of Engineering, Nagpur, India Graduation Date - **May 2012** 

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology, CGPA: 3.0

### **EXPERIENCE**

Sparksoft Corporation, Baltimore, MD, US – Product Development Intern

December 2017 – May 2018

- Counseled to a web-based sandboxing tool built on MEAN stack that mocks REST-based APIs for testing.
- Created REST APIs on NodeJS express framework and integrated them to AnguarJS modules.
- Managed end to end workflow of the application using Agile methodology.

University of Maryland Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD, US – Data Analyst Intern

June 2017 – November 2017

- Collaborated with Maryland State government and researched about the performance of health care providers in Medicare/Medicaid healthcare data in the US.
- Led in designing and developing predictive models and algorithms for efficient data analysis.
- Devised an application that performed data analysis with better storytelling using visualizations for user uploaded dataset, reducing the runtime and increasing efficiency.

#### Tata Consultancy Services, Bangalore, India – Data Analyst

**January 2013 - July 2016** 

- Improved day-to-day operations for over 100 stores for one of the largest retailers in India, providing insights, designing, managing and implementing effective data analysis using business intelligence tool: Tableau.
- Delivered effective business insights, using Python, data warehousing, schema designing, and data reporting.
- Developed an T-SQL module that reduced the time for transfer order creation and improved the process of inventory management system.
- Automated various monthly dynamic dashboard documents for decision makers with multiple panel stacks, selectors, and customized widgets, implementing folder level security by creating security filters.
- Designed module solution which increased the process efficiency by 15 % Key Performance Indicators (KPI).

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Software:Tableau, Data Warehouse, Microsoft Excel, SSRS, SSIS, Data Visualization, SPSSDatabase:Oracle 11i, NoSQL, Mongo, SQLite, SQL, PL/SQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL

**Programming Languages:** R, Python, Java, Shell, RETL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AnguarJS, Express, NodeJS,

**Operating Systems:** Linux - Mint, Ubuntu, Unix, IBM AIX 5.3, Windows Server 2002

# **PROJECTS**

University of Maryland Baltimore County- Automobile accident data in the US August 2017 - December 2017

 Performed data analysis by identifying predictable variables influencing accident deaths from publicly available datasets and performed data cleaning. Testing of dataset by models such as Linear Discriminant Analysis, Quadratic Discriminant Analysis, and K-Nearest Neighbor.

University of Maryland Baltimore County – Electricity Management System August 2016 - December 2016

- Designed a gas and electricity management system, implemented in Oracle 11g including procedures, functions, triggers, packages along with performance tuning and user privileges.
- Optimized SQL queries and procedures to increase performance using SQL Developer.